（四代目風影）
岩隠れの陰謀は阻止した。
We've stopped
the Hidden Stone's schemes!
我が里の勝利へと
また一歩近づいた。
Our village is one step closer
to victory.
今回の作戦の成功は
この者の活躍あってこそ。
We can all thank this person
for the success of the mission!
灼遁のパクラは　砂隠れの英雄だ。
Pakura of the Scorch Style is
a hero of the Hidden Sand!
（マキ）先生！
Sensei!
（パクラ）マキか　どうした？
Maki… What is it?
（マキ）修業をお願いします。
Please train me!
こっちは　任務あけだぞ。
I just finished a mission.
先生でも疲れましたか？
So even you get tired, Sensei?
Honestly…
ったくもう。
は～！
《目くらましか？》
A diversion?
I was so close!
あ～　惜しい！
今のはよかった。
That was good. You would have
caught anyone else.
私でなければ
捕まっていたな。
もう一度お願いします！
Please let me try it
one more time!
焦るんじゃない
お前はきっと強くなる。
Don't get so hasty.
I'm sure you'll become stronger.
そうでしょうか？
Do you think so?
お前が強くなりたいのは
敵討ちのためだろう？
You want to get stronger
to get revenge, right?
はい　父の敵
霧隠れの忍に…。
Yes! I want to avenge my father…
He was killed by a shinobi
of the Hidden Mist…
その思いがあれば　強くなれる。
Those feelings will
make you stronger!
Your feelings for your family, this village,
and your friends in this village…
自分の家族や　この里。
そして里の仲間を大切に思い
里を守り抜くという意志。
and the desire to defend this village…
それが忍を
強くするのだ。
is what makes a shinobi strong!
はい。
Yes!
さて　霧隠れの里との
休戦交渉の件じゃが。
Now then…
about our negotiations for
a truce with the Hidden Mist…
まだまだ　我が里への恨みは
深いようじゃな。
They still seem to hold a deep grudge
toward our village.
Although we made a proposal
that is ridiculously against our favor,
無茶な提案をしておきながら
相変わらず→
they refused to budge.
一切の妥協はせぬとの
一点張りじゃ。
But now is the time for a showdown
with the Hidden Stone!
しかし　今こそ
岩隠れの里との決戦のとき。
後顧の憂いは
断っておくべき。
We shouldn't worry
about the future!
I guess we have no choice.
仕方あるまい
いま一度里のため→
We need Pakura to be useful again…
for the sake of the village.
パクラに役立ってもらわねば。
（四代目風影）
我々の英雄が死んだ。
PAKURA
Our hero… Pakura of the Scorch Style
has died.
灼遁のパクラは決して諦めず
最後まで戦い抜いた。
PAKURA
She never gave up
and fought until the end.
その死を　ムダにしてはならぬ。
We shall not let her death
be in vain!
She died for the village and
we must carry on her will,
里のために死んだ彼女の
砂の意志を受け継ぎ→
今こそ
岩隠れの里を打ち倒すのだ。
and destroy Hidden Stone Village!
（みんな）おぉ～！
《パクラ先生…》
Pakura Sensei…
Ninja Art: Needle Senbon!
忍法　針千本！
Weaklings!
甘いわ！
隊長！
（モンガ）まあ　待て！
Captain…
Wait, don't do anything until
we can get a handle on the situation.
行動を起こすのは
状況を把握してからだ。
モンガ隊長！
Captain Monga!
敵は　大部隊での攻撃ではなく→
The enemy isn't attacking
in large squads…
ゲリラ戦をしかけてきている模様。
but they are using
guerrilla tactics.
相手は　忍刀七人衆です。
We're facing the Seven Ninja
Swords Men of the Mist.
《ミイラ化してる。
He was mummified!
あのお方も　再び
戦闘に加わっているのかしら？》
I wonder if she's fighting again too…
相手が　どこに現れるか
わからん！
We don't know where
the enemy will appear!
警戒を怠るな！
Don't let your guard down!
隊長！　我々も敵の探索に！
Captain! We should search
for the enemy.
我々の出番は戦闘の締めくくりだ。
Our role is to wrap up the battle.
前線からの要請を待て。
Wait until we receive orders
from the front lines!
But there must be something
we can do!
しかし　我々にもできることが…。
Sealing, medical and intel teams
are needed on the battlefield!
封印　医療　通信班は戦場の要だ。
それを守るのが　俺の使命だ。
Our mission is to protect them!
無用な危険に
さらすわけにはいかん。
We can't put ourselves in
unnecessary danger!
（ルカ）そうよ　穢土転生のヤツらの
動きを止められるのは→
That's right.
The only people who can
stop the Reanimation
封印班の人たちだけなんだから。
are the Sealing Corps.
それを言うなら
ルカたち医療班だって…。
But Ruka,
you and the Medical Corps…
Don't worry! As long as I'm here,
安心しろ　俺がいるかぎり→
お前らには　指１本触れさせん。
they won't be able
to lay a finger on you!
俺の命にかけてもな。
I'll risk my life for you.
隊長…。
大丈夫です！
Captain…
It's all right!
隊長に何かあったら　私が
命にかえても助けてみせます。
If something happens
to the captain,
I'll risk my life to save him!
I got it, I got it!
わかった　わかった。
（ザジ）忍刀もないのに　強い。
He's strong even without
a ninja blade!
（オモイ）けど　敵は１人。
But there's only one of him.
もっと大人数で囲んで
波状攻撃をかければ→
If we surround him with more people
and attack in waves…
スキも生じるはず。
that should create
an opportunity for us…
苦戦しているようだな。
Seems like it's a tough fight.
相手が　相手ですからね。
It is him we're fighting…
ねえ　マキちゃん。　なんで
大部隊で攻めて来ないのかな？
Hey, Maki, why aren't they attacking
with a large squad?
わからない。　とにかく
相手の出方を見極めて→
I don't know…
Anyway, we need to figure out
what the enemy is going to do
and put together a strategy.
対策を練らないと。
あっ！　うわっ！
How many enemies are there?
敵は何人だ？
わかりません。
I don't know.
They just suddenly appeared.
いきなり現れて…。
マキ　ルカ！　お前たちは下がってろ！
Maki, Ruka! Fall back!
（ガリ）すぐに逃げたほうがいいぞ。
Perhaps you should tell them
to run as fast as they can…
でなきゃ　すぐにドカンだ。
If they don't, they'll go boom.
爆遁のガリ！
Gari of the Explosion Style…
あなたが相手だとは…。
I never expected to face you…
そうだな　俺の相手にしては
人数不足だな。
Yeah, you don't have
enough men to take me on.
まさに　こちらの思惑どおり。
That's exactly what
we want you to think…
《派手なゲリラ戦は
戦力を分散させるための陽動か》
I get it! The flashy guerrilla tactics are
just to scatter our forces.
最初から後方支援部隊を
狙っていたということか。
You were targeting
the support squads in the rear
from the beginning, huh?
そのほうが
戦闘を終わらす近道だろ？
That's the quickest way
to end the battle, isn't it?
それに　せっかく生き返った
体の自由を奪う封印の術は→
Besides, I've been brought
back to life and
I can't stand being immobile
because of a Sealing Jutsu.
特に我慢ならないからな。
あなたほどのお方が
操り人形の身で満足だとは。
I never expected someone
like you to be satisfied
with being just a puppet…
そんなことは
一度も死んだことのない野郎に→
You've never been dead,
so you wouldn't understand.
言われたかねえな。
Death isn't something
to take lightly!
死とは
そんなに軽いものではない！
Earth Style: Mud Slide!
土遁　土石筍！
ヤツには　うかつに近づくな！
Don't get near him!
悪いな。
Sorry, your advice has
fallen on deaf ears…
せっかくの助言を
無駄にしちまって。
（マキ）モンガ隊長　私が…。
（モンガ）お前たちは　そこにいろ！
Captain Monga, I…
You guys stay there!
ここは俺１人で十分だ。
I can handle this by myself.
How fun…
おもしろい。
だが　気合だけじゃ止められんぞ！
But you can't stop me
with just spirit!
そんなもので爆遁が防げるのか？
Can you defend yourself against
Explosion Style with just that?
やりましたね　モンガ隊長！
You did it, Captain Monga!
あぁ　だが…。
Yeah.
But…
マキ　すぐにヤツを封印しろ！
Maki, seal him away right away.
（ルカ）隊長！
Captain!
《この術は…》
This jutsu is…
《パクラ先生！》
Pakura Sensei…
パクラ先生…。
お前　マキか？
You're…Maki?
まさか　こんな形で
再会することになるとは。
I never expected to
see you again, like this.
顔の隈取りは変わっていないな。
Your face paint hasn't changed.
マキちゃん　先生って…。
Maki, what do you mean
by "Sensei"?
このお方は
かつての砂隠れの英雄。
She was once
the Hidden Sand's hero.
そして
私を忍として鍛えてくれた師匠。
She is also the person
who trained me to become a shinobi.
生き返ってみたら
驚くことばかりだな。
Coming back to life has
been full of surprises.
Why are you fighting, Sensei?
先生　なぜ戦うんです？
今は自分の意志で
動けるのではないですか？
Can't you move by
your own free will?
知れたこと。
この無念の思いを晴らすためだ。
It's simple!
To vent my frustration…
at being banished to the darkness
of death and being silenced!
無念を晴らす？
Vent your frustration?
I was made into the village hero.
里の英雄ともてはやされ→
And after all that praise,
さんざん持ち上げられた
挙句の果てに→
I was sacrificed as a pawn
for the benefit of the village.
里の利益のために
捨て駒にされた　この悔しさ。
This frustration… This anger…
この怒り。
私を利用した里の幹部連中は
とっくに　この世を去った。
The ones who used me
are long gone,
but the village that killed me is
a painful reminder that still exists.
だが　私を殺した
霧隠れの里の連中は目障りだ。
That's right!
そうさ　霧隠れの里の連中を
根絶やしにするために→
I'm fighting to eradicate
the Village Hidden in the Mist!
私は戦うんだよ。
The Village Hidden in the Mist?
霧隠れの里？
先生は　岩隠れの里との戦で
命を落としたと…。
I heard that you had died fighting
the Hidden Stone.
それは私の死をも
都合よく利用しようとした→
That was a story made up
by our superiors
to take advantage of my death.
里の上層部の作り話。
私はあの日
死の間際ですべてを悟ったのだ。
That day, I realized everything
just before I died…
私は風影様じきじきの命により→
The Kazekage ordered me to
the Hidden Mist Village as an envoy.
使者として
霧隠れの里へと向かった。
極秘任務ということで
密かに里を抜け出してな。
It was a top-secret mission,
so I left in secret.
((灼遁のパクラ殿。
Pakura of the Scorch Style!
お出迎えにまいりました。
We've come to welcome you.
お目にかかれて光栄です。
It is an honor to meet you.
なにせ　この霧ですからな→
This mist shrouds us,
道案内が必要かと。
so we thought you would need
someone to lead the way.
ご苦労であった。
Thank you very much.
But there is no way I would
get lost going through this valley.
しかし　この谷を抜けるまでは
迷いようがあるまい。
Very true!
いや　ごもっとも。
では　お先に。
Well, please proceed.
Fine.
ああ。
W-What are you doing?!
な　なにを…。
砂隠れの里に殺された
仲間たちの苦しみ→
Feel the pain felt by our comrades
who were killed by your village!
思い知れ！
勘違いするな。
Don't get the wrong idea.
Don't think that this will
get rid of our grudge.
これで我が里の恨みが
消えたと思うなよ。
貴様の犠牲なぞ
ほんの気休め程度に過ぎん。
Your sacrifice is
but a small comfort.
貴様を差し出した
砂隠れの里の連中も→
The ones from the Hidden Sand
who handed you over are
probably thinking that.
(きっとそう思っているはず))
私は霧隠れの里との取り引きに
使われたのさ。
I was used as a bargaining chip
with the Village Hidden in the Mist…
里の利益のためにな。
to benefit our village.
まさか…。
Impossible…
ひどい。
How horrible…
見たところ　ここにも１人
紛れ込んでるみたいだね。
From what I can see,
seems one of them has slipped
into your ranks…
血霧の忍が。
A Bloody Mist shinobi, huh?
それは過去の話です。
That was all in the past!
今は五代目水影様のもと→
The Fifth Mizukage has ushered
in a new age for the Hidden Mist!
霧隠れは新しい時代を迎えたから。
それで
過去を消せるとでもいうのか！
Do you think that erases
your past?!
The Hidden Mist's history
of blood and treachery?
霧隠れの血と謀略の歴史を。
やめてください　パクラ先生。
Please stop, Pakura Sensei!
恨むのなら　信頼を裏切った
自分の里ではありませんか？
If you want to blame something,
blame our village for
betraying your trust!
You should blame
the Hidden Sand
忠誠を尽くした英雄を
あっさりと捨てた砂隠れこそ→
for casting aside a loyal hero
such as yourself!
責めるべきではありませんか？
正直
私も今の先生の話を聞いて→
In all honestly, I'm still confused
by your story.
まだ混乱しています。
だからといって
自分の恨みを晴らすために→
But I strongly believe that
it's wrong to attack people
関係ない人たちに
手をかけることは→
who have nothing to do
with your grudge!
間違いだということは
はっきりと言えます。
They are involved!
関係なくはない！
That's because
you can't see it, Sensei!
それは
先生には見えていないからです。
忍連合で戦ってみて
わかりました。
I've learned something while fighting
in the Allied Shinobi Force.
Even people who were once
prejudiced against other villages
今まで　どこの里の忍かという→
偏見でしか
見ていなかった人々でも→
can work together, talk together,
一緒に行動したり
直接話してみれば→
understand each other,
and cooperate!
お互い理解し　協力だって
できるのだということを。
ならば…。
If that's the case…
If that's the case…!
ならば　この胸の奥に
凝り固まった恨みは→
Who can get rid of this grudge
that festers deep in my heart?!
誰が晴らしてくれる？
Are you telling me that
it can't be helped,
どうしようもなかったことだと→
and that I should just give up?!
ただあきらめろとでも言うのか？
それは…。
Well…
戯れ言は　もういい。
Enough talk!
My body has been reanimated.
どの道　穢土転生された　この体だ。
I cannot go against my orders
to fight the Allied Shinobi Force!
忍連合と戦えという命令からは
逃れられない。
お前らは逃げろ。
You guys run away.
But take this transmitter…
ただ　この通信機だけは…。
ここは私に任せて。
Leave this to me!
布隠れの術！
Hidden Cloth Jutsu!
That was a good move.
いい判断だ
だが　どこまで逃げられるかな！
I wonder how far
you can run away.
あの人と　まともに戦ってはダメ。
We can't fight her normally.
他の部隊と合流しなければ。
We need to regroup with
the rest of the team.
連絡を取ってみる。
I'll try to contact them!
助かったわ　ルカ。
You saved us, Ruka.
私の水遁も
なかなかのものでしょ。
My Water Style is pretty good, huh?
すまんな　俺は役立たずで。
Sorry, I'm so useless…
ここだったか。
So this is where you were.
私と戦うのもムリだが
逃げることもムリのようだな。
You can't fight me,
and it seems you can't run away
from me either.
どうする？　このまま
かくれんぼを続けるか？
What will you do?
Are we going to continue to
play hide-and-seek?
先生
これだけは言わせてください。
Sensei… Just let me say this.
過去は消せない　だけど
未来は　これから作れます。
You cannot erase the past,
but you can help create the future!
I believe that our experiences,
from fighting in the Allied Shinobi Force,
忍連合として　戦った経験は→
きっと　その後の里の関係を
変えてくれると→
will change future relations
between the villages!
私は信じています。
昔のような愚かな過ちを犯さない
新しい忍の世界に。
We'll have a new shinobi world
that won't make
the terrible mistakes of the past.
だから　パクラ先生は→
So, Pakura Sensei, you died
as a hero of the Hidden Sand…
砂隠れの英雄として死んだ
あなたは→
英雄のままで　いてください。
Please remain a hero.
This is one flashy fight…
こっちは　派手に戦ってるな。
Zaji, Omoi!
ザジ　オモイ！
悪い　遅くなった。
Sorry we're late.
We ran into some trouble.
ちょっとばかり
手間取っちまってな。
Now!
((今だ！
(やったか？))
Did we get him?
こっちの敵は　血継限界か。
Our enemy has a Kekkei Genkai.
（マキ）あの火の玉を食らったら
終わりです。
If you get hit with that fireball,
it's all over.
But we'll cover you!
でも　私たちが防ぎます。
頼んだっすよ。
We're counting on you.
はぁ！！
– Ruka!
– Okay!
ルカ！
はい。
Gotcha!
あっ！
They multiplied?
増えんのかよ！
Don't stop moving!
動きを止めないで。
やるようになったね　マキ
だが　捕まるわけにはいかない！
I see you've learned
how to do it, Maki.
But I can't let you capture me!
《今だ！》
Now!
Ruka! On my signal,
use maximum water power!
ルカ　合図で最大水力。
ザジ！
Zaji!
Come on, Maki! Come at me!
さあ　マキ　来てみな！
その前に　俺が相手だ！
Before that, I'll fight you.
素直じゃないね
じゃあ　まずは　お前からだ！
You're being difficult.
Well then,
I'll take care of you first!
Ruka!
ルカ！
I'm the one who'll get you!
本命は俺だ！
くっ！
捕らえた！
We've got her!
爆遁！
Explosion Style!
Gari of the Explosion Style!
爆遁のガリ！
まずい…。
This is bad…
More people showed up
out of nowhere.
いつの間にか
人数増えてんじゃねえか。
なんだ　パクラ　そのざまは。
You're a mess, Pakura.
俺の復活が　もう少し遅れてたら
危ないところだったな。
If I had recovered a little later,
it would have been
all over for you.
コイツら　そんなに強いのか？
Are these guys that strong?
《強くなったな　マキ》
You've gotten strong, Maki…
この体のいいところは
やり直しがきくってことだな。
The good thing about this body
is that I can revive quickly.
それじゃあ　続きを始めようか。
Well, let's continue.
まずは　厄介な封印のヤツから。
I'm going to take out
that pesky sealer first.
そうはいかないな。
We're not goi
アンタを　もうやり直しが
できないように→
してもらうんすから。
お前らこそ
やり直しがきかないって→
あの世で嘆くなよ。
何の真似だ　パクラ？
子供は自分で
痛い目をみなければ学ばない。
だから　そのチャンスを
与えたくなった。
未来を変えられるかも
しれないチャンスを。
意味がわからんな。
昔の仲間に情けを
かけたということか。
そう　とってもらって構わない。
逃げろ　マキ！
私の意識があるうちに！
言うことを聞いたほうが
よさそうだな。
２人が相手となったら
ちょっと　キツイっすね。
行こう　マキ！
マキちゃん。
行こう　ルカ。
灼遁のパクラ。
お前とは　一度
手合わせしたいと思っていたが→
それも　叶わぬ夢だな。
ああ　意識が奪われていく。
《マキ…》
まだ　他の部隊と
連絡つかねえのかよ？
ちょっと静かにしてください。
ただでさえ
聞こえづらいんですから。
あれ　マキは？
えっ？　さっきまで　そこに…。
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１２名の皆さんによる→